<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Page on William Parker&#39;s Personal Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Page on William Parker&#39;s Personal Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</webMaster>
    <copyright>William Parker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The intention of this site is to provide a place where I can record the past projects I worked on.
It&amp;rsquo;s meant to be somewhere between a portfolio and a retrospective blog, where I discuss what I
worked on from a technical perspective and show off the design process behind the features that were added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The date of the post the approximate date I finished the project, not the date of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of all of the posts I have planned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Moore&amp;rsquo;s Falls Eagle Scout Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; APCSA TA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; SNHU Computer Science Club VP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; FreeMoveVR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; SJSU MS Thesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Unified Live Chat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; SJSU MS AI Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; SNHU Comp Sci Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; 3tene ahk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Eventified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; FlightSure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; ChordLlama&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Multi-Repo Coding Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Pond Jumper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; RoundHouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Yabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Flutter M BLE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Google Mediapipe Pose Detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Arity Android Engineer Intern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AP Computer Science A Teacher&#39;s Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/ap-comp-sci-a-ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/ap-comp-sci-a-ta/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By my senior year in high school, I had nearly complete freedom to do what I wanted,
so I chose to help teach programming to my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people can probably agree that high school can be as easy as you want it to be.
In my school, I needed a total of 24 credits. There were eight class slots per year.
One of those slots was often taken up by a free block, so the average student often
would gain seven a semester. Even if you complexly fail a class every semester,
you would still have six credits a year, multiplied by four years will give you the
24 credits needed to graduate. If you do well in school, you could easily skip the
free block and have eight credits a year, which means you would be theoretically able
to graduate a whole year early. Anyone that was that smart though would spend time
working on AP classes to get a head start in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had taken AP Computer Science A (APCSA) my junior year of high school over VLACS, as the class
was effectively self taught due to lack of teachers and limited demand for the class.
VLACS was an online curriculum which can substitute classes in your high school, and
unbeknownst to me it would become my favorite class would take in high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My class felt heavily more academic than most years students, and that could be seen&lt;br&gt;
in the growth of students applying for APCSA my senior year. In my junior year
the teacher had &amp;ldquo;taught&amp;rdquo; 2 students, this time there were 15, all of which I would
consider my friends as we had a relatively small school. I decided to talk to the
computer science teacher at the school to judge if I should be a teacher&amp;rsquo;s assistant (TA),
and from what I remember he pretty much admitted that he did not have the ability to teach
the course as his job at the school consisted of teaching Scratch projects and extremely
basic Python for many years, and he was not aware of how the College Board&amp;rsquo;s AP tests worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a good student. Not the best, but was still proud of my accomplishments because as I
stated my class felt extremely academic compared to average. None of the classes I wanted to
take interfered with the APCSA time slot, and I learned that both of the other students that took the class
with the teacher last year failed. Due to all this, I felt obligated to my friends to help teach
the course as a TA with this teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-teaching&#34;&gt;Starting Teaching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I had to maintain an interesting balance of not overshadowing the teacher, teaching the students
what was needed for the test, and not turning my friendly relationships into ones of teacher and student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I had taught others that actually depended on the accuracy of what I said.
Sure there were times in Boys Scouts or talking through what to do in a game, but nothing at this level.
This combination of figuring out how I wanted to teach for the first time and the interesting set of
social circumstances I was in allowed me to not only create a
unique teaching style that worked for me and my peers but also a love for teaching within myself.
I was taking a few other AP classes as well and found the lectures of those classes extremely boring with
little interaction and way too much memorization. I felt like I could have the students remember much more
if I taught in a more interactive way without trimming down on content. A metric I used was that I felt like I was doing
a good job if everyone agreed we were keeping on pace for the test while the class felt like a social break where we discussed
interesting topics and how to solve new problems that I could get the class invested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-a-chill-guy&#34;&gt;Just a Chill Guy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would often discuss with the teacher what topics we should cover, and ask to present on them in class.
When I presented, instead of lecturing, I led a conversation with my students like an interactive live show,
where I would make sure my entire thought process of a problem was explainable in plain English, and talk through
solutions that everyone could get behind in theory
as we wrote them out and tested. Students could interject almost whenever they wanted, and I often asked for random
inputs from the students for critical components, which often ended up entertaining everyone including myself while
staying on track and learning about what we needed. I taught much of the course as thinking of physical objects that could
be manipulated though what we write. One of my favorite exercises was trying to explain sorting algorithms by
moving around playing cards, defining all of the possible moves in terms of what we learned so far in class, and letting the
students try to figure out the sorting algorithms themselves in a gamified way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having in-class programming also was extremely fun for me and the students. We always did some sort of pair programming,
as it is much more fun talking and bouncing ideas off each other and it is good practice in the industry.
Additionally, I was able to see the wide variety of solutions that everyone was able to come up with. While the students
didn&amp;rsquo;t understand why I was taking so long at first, almost every pair had a different approach to the problem.
This showed me that programming is inherently creative. Technically, there is probably an optimal solution, but
like deciding on a JavaScript framework, where that type of discussion quickly becomes irrelevant most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire year I had fun teaching the class and I felt like the students enjoyed coming every day.
The teacher loved all of the work and dedication I put in over the school year. While we did butt heads at times,
we were great teammates. My peers in my class also could sense my dedication and commitment to keep the class
light-hearted and bragged about being in my class or talked about how well I could explain concepts even when we
were with other students outside the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teacher&amp;rsquo;s assistants are discouraged from knowing the grades of the students they teach. Even so, I know that one
of my best friends from the class passed, and that he said the whole class had done reasonably well. The coronavirus
pandemic hit at the end of the year, so not much happened after the test, but at graduation I was awarded the top
computer science student of the year. An honor I was proud of receiving as a student that never took a programming
class at the school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pond Jumper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/pond-jumper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/pond-jumper/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My First Large Project: an Arcade Game for Smart Phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at how I first learned software development, I feel very fortunate to have taken the path I did.
In my junior year of high school I took &lt;a href=&#34;https://apstudents.collegeboard.org/courses/ap-computer-science-a&#34;&gt;AP Computer Science A&lt;/a&gt;,
which was taught extremely thoroughly on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vlacs.org/&#34;&gt;VLACS&lt;/a&gt; and
is probably the best course I took in high school despite it being online. My senior year I needed to do a senior
project, and for this, I decided to re-implement an idea I had made previously, reimagining it using &lt;a href=&#34;https://unity.com/&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past-projects/pond_jumper/pond_jumper_home.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pond Jumper Title&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pond Jumper Title Screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;game-inspiration&#34;&gt;Game Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time I had recently played &lt;a href=&#34;https://undertale.com/&#34;&gt;Undertale&lt;/a&gt;. The main action of the game is a bullet-hell system where you control
a small character that needs to move and avoid obstacles. While many aspects of Undertale are unique, a core part of
the game focuses on special mechanics in boss battles. During these scenes, the normal rules of the fights change and the
novelty of additional rules applied to the core bullet-hell mechanic are explored and become more complex throughout the battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the concepts I had wished there were more of were in the middle of the game, in the Undyne and Muffet battles. The
Undyne battle complexly changed the idea of a bullet-hell, where instead of avoiding the bullets, you had a shield and needed
to block them. The Muffet battle had the player jumping between pre-defined tracks to avoid the bullets which differed from the normal
game where you have complete control over the movement of your character to any point within the arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past-projects/pond_jumper/undyne_fight.png&#34; alt=&#34;Undyne Fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Undyne Fight in Undertale. Image source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dualshockers.com/undertale-hardest-boss-fights/&#34;&gt;DualShockers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past-projects/pond_jumper/muffet_fight.png&#34; alt=&#34;Muffet Fight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Muffet Fight in Undertale. Image source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://images.app.goo.gl/u9M4df3RGqbQuyYHA&#34;&gt;Very Vennie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many bullet-hell styled games did exist, these takes on the genre rarely seemed to have been expanded upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-attempt&#34;&gt;Early Attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a introductory computer class I took in high school my sophomore year, we were required to create a game in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scratch.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I had wanted to learn to code, but genuinely had no clue about
how to get started with programming. I was excited to show what I could do in code if I was able to write,
so I worked tirelessly to create the game I was imagining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to combine the concepts of the Undyne and Muffet fights into one. Instead of three tracks like Muffet,
I made it a 5x5 grid where the player jumps between cells. I then took the idea of the Undyne fight, and made some bullets
able to be blocked by a shield that rotated around the player. Additionally, some bullets were not able
to be blocked so the player needed to both move around and block to survive. The game is still playable on Scratch as
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scratch.mit.edu/projects/214045899/&#34;&gt;5x5 Bullet Avoid Game&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by WillPar. I definitely over-achieved in the
assignment, and I think I got a 98% if I recall correctly. The teacher took off 2 points because I did not specify
in the instructions that by WASD I was referring to the keys on the keyboard to move the character (she was an art teacher
and not well-versed in technology).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past-projects/pond_jumper/scratch_game.png&#34; alt=&#34;5x5 Bullet Avoid Game&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My first game on Scratch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pond-jumper&#34;&gt;Pond Jumper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the start of my senior year in high school and I knew I wanted to make a game in Unity. I understood that C# was close
to Java, and I knew Java well from taking AP Computer Science A the previous year. I had a few ideas but none of them stuck as well
as taking another shot at my bullet-hell idea. This time I wanted to make it 3D, with better graphics, and playable on mobile with swiping
as the main input method. I would call the app &amp;ldquo;Pond Jumper&amp;rdquo;, and theme the game around a character with a shield blocking birds while
jumping between lily pads on a pond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first time writing code other than in Java for a class, and I was surprised about how easily the language concepts from Java were
able to transfer to this project. The biggest change was that I was using a framework for the first time, and while I didn&amp;rsquo;t completely
understand some of the parts of the framework and all of the new options presented to me, I found that creating a game was probably the
best way for me to be introduced to the concept of a framework. Coding tutorials for games are some of the most common types of coding
tutorials, and extremely high-quality sources exist like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYbK_tjZ2OrIZFBvU6CCMiA&#34;&gt;Brackeys&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube.
These early lessons about working with the framework I found to not really be taught in college, but a critical part of knowing how to build
any sort of real application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use prebuilt assets from the Unity Asset Store. I had made clear that I was building the app as an exercise in programming,
and not for the artistic side, so this was fine to do. There was also no sound, but the prebuilt assets did have animations for when
the player died at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/past-projects/pond_jumper/pond_jumper_game.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen capture while playing Pond Jumper&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of Pond Jumper mid-game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programming for the game honestly was not bad in comparison to all of the work I needed to do for AP Computer Science A, and despite
having an incredible senior project for the school it felt like the coding was easy for what I was doing. It heavily relied on
timers to know when to spawn bullets, or now birds to match the theme with my assets, and to properly give points to the player. I needed to
keep track of the birds despawning once they were out of range of the camera, and I made a predefined jump script for the character so that it
always looked like it was on a grid tile, or now lily pad for movement. I learned about game balancing, making sure that the game became more
difficult as the game went on so that it would not be endlessly boring, and added additional assets to the game so it was interesting to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final component of the project was releasing the app to the Google Play Store. I chose to only release to the Play Store,
as I had an Android phone, and that Google has a one-time cost to publish compared to the yearly cost on iOS. The publishing process was
much easier back then than it is today. Google now requires 20 beta testers before launch, but that requirement did not exist
at all in 2020. Additionally, Unity had clear instructions on how to build the game to be published to the Play Store, and I learned how to
publish to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, I forgot to check the email associated with the project. Unity deleted the cloud backup of the project
and the Play Store took down the game due to inactivity. While there is not much of a record of the game anymore,
the app can still be downloaded from mirror sites like on APK Pure from the link below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apkpure.com/pond-jumper/com.WilliamParker.PondJumper&#34;&gt;https://apkpure.com/pond-jumper/com.WilliamParker.PondJumper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moore&#39;s Falls Historical Plaques Eagle Scout Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/moores-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/moores-falls/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every town has their stories of how they were created and developed over the years.
In my hometown of Litchfield, New Hampshire, I had the opportunity to re-discover that history and
create historical plaques about it for visitors to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project consisted of five pages, or plaques, spread through the trail loop slowly explaining the
historical significance of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Moore%27s&amp;#43;Falls&amp;#43;Conservation&amp;#43;Area/@42.889804,-71.4576986,802m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x89e24cbf7350056d:0xed373f3adc07f897!8m2!3d42.8898001!4d-71.4551237!16s%2Fg%2F11c528d249?entry=ttu&amp;amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MDIwNC4wIKXMDSoASAFQAw%3D%3D&#34;&gt;Moore&amp;rsquo;s Falls Trail&lt;/a&gt;
over the course of the hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project consisted of several factors. Funding for the project needed to be secured via work with local businesses and the local newspaper.
Stakeholders needed updates on the project and proof of work to approve the necessary steps. The most notable stakeholder was
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/litchfieldnhconservationcommission/&#34;&gt;The Litchfield Conservation Commission&lt;/a&gt;, a governmental board of the town
responsible for the trails and the group that originally requested the project. Finally, it required organizing and leading a team of
scouts in building and setting the plaques across the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, the original writings were a bit long considering the length of the trail, but it was a culmination of
research between multiple town historians, including Chuck Mower, The book
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/books/edition/The_Incredible_Ditch/DmGCsEpGExQC&#34;&gt;The Incredible Ditch: A Bicentennial History of the Middlesex Canal&lt;/a&gt;,
and most notably &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.middlesexcanal.org/&#34;&gt;The Middlesex Canal Association&lt;/a&gt;,
a historical group and museum dedicated to preserving the history of the canal system on the Merrimack River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I would like to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://lccpnh.org/scouts-bsa/&#34;&gt;BSA Troop 11&lt;/a&gt;, as the project would not have been possible without them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;object
    data=&#34;/community-work/moores-falls/moores_falls_combined.pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;800px&#34;type=&#34;application/pdf&#34;
&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unable to display PDF file. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/community-work/moores-falls/moores_falls_combined.pdf&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/current-projects/thesis-selective-pose-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/current-projects/thesis-selective-pose-detection/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/education/snhu-comp-sci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/education/snhu-comp-sci/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/3tene-ahk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/3tene-ahk/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/chord-llama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/chord-llama/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/eventified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/eventified/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/flight-sure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/flight-sure/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/multi-repo-coding-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/multi-repo-coding-assistant/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/roundhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/roundhouse/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/yabi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/past-projects/yabi/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/flutter-m-ble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/flutter-m-ble/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/google-mediapipe-pose-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/google-mediapipe-pose-detection/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
