<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on William Parker&#39;s Personal Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on William Parker&#39;s Personal Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</webMaster>
    <copyright>William Parker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Scheduler Search in TVM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/tvm-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/tvm-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Compiler Frameworks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvm.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache TVM&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tvm.apache.org/2021/03/03/intro-auto-scheduler&#34;&gt;Ansor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;optimize schedulers for inference. The software runs a search algorithm, optimizing&#xA;a model for the specific hardware configuration. Apache TVM integrates with all popular&#xA;model frameworks, allowing for optimizations in inference latency, improved throughput,&#xA;and memory usage optimization. For this project, we combine and evaluate the efficiency&#xA;of two additional techniques used to improve Ansor:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gicLAB/transfer-tuning/tree/main&#34;&gt;transfer-tuning&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3650109&#34;&gt;droplet search&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;In our tests, we find that combining these two techniques can lead to an improvement of up&#xA;to 10% faster inference than using transfer-tuning alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi Repo Coding Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/multi-repo-coding-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/multi-repo-coding-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applying LLM routing for a single chat across multiple repositories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on combine multiple repositories to create a single experience&#xA;for the user. There are many common examples of this, like a full-stack developer working on&#xA;the front and back end. It gets much more complex though as the scope of the application grows. Companies&#xA;may want development teams for Android and iOS, and this requires teams to understand where each&#xA;other team is at to maintain feature parity. There are many questions that a developer of one team&#xA;could have, and discussion on every technical intricacy can take time from development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlightSure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/flight-sure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/flight-sure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using Machine Learning to Find the Chance a Flight is on Time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had recently returned to San Jose after visiting my family across the country.&#xA;While waiting at Logan Airport in Boston, I was watching the snowfall and wondered&#xA;if it would delay my flight. It had just started and light snow is a normal occurrence for&#xA;the area, so it was unlikely but possible. I then considered San Jose&amp;rsquo;s Airport. While they have&#xA;different weather they need to account for, there is no infrastructure in place for even&#xA;light snow. In addition, many drivers would not know how to handle slippery roads, which&#xA;would probably cause significant problems across the city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chord Llama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/chord-llama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/chord-llama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fine-tuning Llama for sheet music generation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have recently reached a critical mass in the public eye,&#xA;where everyone is trying to apply the technology to any problem they can think of.&#xA;They have been further trained, or fine-tuned, for a variety of use cases, be it for&#xA;business, software development, or speaking languages outside their original training&#xA;data. At the time, I had recently learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/2021/06/musicxml40/&#34;&gt;MusicXML&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;which is the format used for sheet music. An application like &lt;a href=&#34;https://musescore.org/en&#34;&gt;MuseScore&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;is used to write music sheets for musicians and saves the work to a &lt;code&gt;.MXL&lt;/code&gt; file so it can be&#xA;redistributed and edited without the pains of using a proprietary file type or making&#xA;the sheets by hand and scanning them with a printer. MusicXML has been a standard since 2004&#xA;and managed by W3C by 2015. As it is a pretty widely accepted standard, we looked into&#xA;understanding how an LLM like Llama could be fine-tuned on this data to continue existing music&#xA;or generate its own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mediapipe Pose Detection: Flutter Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/google-mediapipe-pose-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/google-mediapipe-pose-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Flutter library for pose detection using Google&amp;rsquo;s Mediapipe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before 2023, Google&amp;rsquo;s solution for machine learning (ML) on mobile was&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/ml-kit/&#34;&gt;ML Kit&lt;/a&gt;. The library was for Android and iOS&#xA;and had a variety of small models to perform common tasks that developers could use for&#xA;their apps. This was before LLMs took over the public mind, so the platform heavily focused&#xA;on computer vision for tasks like facial detection and image labeling.&#xA;The library was well received by many developers and the developer community was even&#xA;interested enough in the library that it was ported to Flutter for&#xA;iOS and Android as &lt;a href=&#34;https://pub.dev/packages/google_ml_kit&#34;&gt;google_ml_kit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peripheral BLE Library for Flutter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/m-ble-peripheral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/software-libraries/m-ble-peripheral/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing a Flutter library with full BLE peripheral capabilities for iOS and Android&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bluetooth-for-freemovevr&#34;&gt;Bluetooth For FreeMoveVR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early on in the creation of FreeMoveVR, I knew I wanted the primary communication&#xA;method between the smartphone and computer to be over Bluetooth. I believed that&#xA;Bluetooth was the perfect solution for our use case because:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everyone has Bluetooth on their phone, and it is a stable option for developers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FreeMoveVR needs to transfer a relatively small amount of data compared to something like streaming music to AirPods.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s wireless, so there is less hassle setting up the program for the end user.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It does not rely on Wi-Fi at all, which is good in cases like colleges where the protocols are very complex and locked down for students.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BLE stands for Bluetooth Low Energy, so the implication is that the phone can do the main task of pose detection and spend minimal resources on data transfer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most notable arguments against the other methods were that a wired connection would be hard to use given how the app works,&#xA;and that a Wi-Fi connection would be impossible to develop while on campus at SNHU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eventified</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/eventified/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/eventified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Android calendar app for university clubs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-slide hover-effect-zoom hover-transition&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageGallery&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;/mobile-projects/eventified/androidStack.jpg&#39;);&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/mobile-projects/eventified/androidStack.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/mobile-projects/eventified/androidStack.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(&#39;/mobile-projects/eventified/homescreen.png&#39;);&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/mobile-projects/eventified/homescreen.png&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/mobile-projects/eventified/homescreen.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;arriving-at-snhu&#34;&gt;Arriving at SNHU&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was my first semester on campus at Southern New Hampshire University (SNHU).&#xA;Covid was the year prior, so my class along with the cohort below me was new to the campus.&#xA;I had experience with Java in my high school and even &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/ap-comp-sci-a-ta/&#34;&gt;taught the AP course on it&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;They also taught Java in the first coding class of SNHU,&#xA;so going into my second year I figured I would want to use it in team-based projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3tene AutoHotKey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/3tene-autohotkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai-projects/3tene-autohotkey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allowing VTubers to express themselves through global hotkeys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-vtubing-and-3tene&#34;&gt;Finding VTubing and 3tene&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the coronavirus pandemic hit and society was in lockdown, I started watching more Twitch.&#xA;Around this time, VTubing was taking off, as people could remain semi-anonymous online while&#xA;attempting to grow a following on video-based platforms. The concept was in good fun and not too serious&#xA;as you would expect from a mildly popular casual entertainment genre. This was my first look at human&#xA;positional tracking systems, and I was impressed with the underlying technology. The problem often was in&#xA;the feature set of the applications used for this growing genre of entertainment, where key features I&#xA;would expect to find in popularly recommended apps seemed to be missing for the technology to&#xA;be used more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AP Computer Science A Teacher&#39;s Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/ap-comp-sci-a-ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/ap-comp-sci-a-ta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By my senior year in high school, I had nearly complete freedom to do what I wanted,&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;so I chose to help teach programming to my friends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people can probably agree that high school can be as easy as you want it to be.&#xA;In my school, I needed a total of 24 credits. There were eight class slots per year.&#xA;One of those slots was often taken up by a free block, so the average student often&#xA;would gain seven a semester. Even if you complexly fail a class every semester,&#xA;you would still have six credits a year, multiplied by four years will give you the&#xA;24 credits needed to graduate. If you do well in school, you could easily skip the&#xA;free block and have eight credits a year, which means you would be theoretically able&#xA;to graduate a whole year early. Anyone that was that smart though would spend time&#xA;working on AP classes to get a head start in college.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pond Jumper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/pond-jumper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/pond-jumper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My First Large Project: an Arcade Game for Smart Phones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back at how I first learned software development, I feel very fortunate to have taken the path I did.&#xA;In my junior year of high school I took &lt;a href=&#34;https://apstudents.collegeboard.org/courses/ap-computer-science-a&#34;&gt;AP Computer Science A&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;which was taught extremely thoroughly on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vlacs.org/&#34;&gt;VLACS&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;is probably the best course I took in high school despite it being online. My senior year I needed to do a senior&#xA;project, and for this, I decided to re-implement an idea I had made previously, reimagining it using &lt;a href=&#34;https://unity.com/&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moore&#39;s Falls Historical Plaques Eagle Scout Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/moores-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/community-work/moores-falls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every town has their stories of how they were created and developed over the years.&#xA;In my hometown of Litchfield, New Hampshire, I had the opportunity to re-discover that history and&#xA;create historical plaques about it for visitors to see.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project consisted of five pages, or plaques, spread through the trail loop slowly explaining the&#xA;historical significance of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Moore%27s&amp;#43;Falls&amp;#43;Conservation&amp;#43;Area/@42.889804,-71.4576986,802m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x89e24cbf7350056d:0xed373f3adc07f897!8m2!3d42.8898001!4d-71.4551237!16s%2Fg%2F11c528d249?entry=ttu&amp;amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI1MDIwNC4wIKXMDSoASAFQAw%3D%3D&#34;&gt;Moore&amp;rsquo;s Falls Trail&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;over the course of the hike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project consisted of several factors. Funding for the project needed to be secured via work with local businesses and the local newspaper.&#xA;Stakeholders needed updates on the project and proof of work to approve the necessary steps. The most notable stakeholder was&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/litchfieldnhconservationcommission/&#34;&gt;The Litchfield Conservation Commission&lt;/a&gt;, a governmental board of the town&#xA;responsible for the trails and the group that originally requested the project. Finally, it required organizing and leading a team of&#xA;scouts in building and setting the plaques across the trail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/education/snhu-comp-sci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/education/snhu-comp-sci/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/pocket-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/pocket-llm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/yabi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mobile-projects/yabi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/personal-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/personal-site/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/roundhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/roundhouse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/unified-live-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>wiparker2020@gmail.com (William Parker)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/web-projects/unified-live-chat/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
